

# Giampaolo Carducci

Main roles: CVQ Engineer (clean utilities) / Civil construction supervisor

City: Bern

**Nationality: ITALIAN** 

Language: IT/EN/DE(A2)

Experienced Civil/Industrial Engineer with a Master degree in Environmental Engineering, with more than 6+ years of experience in Consulting gather along different Pharmaceutical Clients.

I have CQV background mainly focused on **Clean and Black utilities** (SW - PW - WFI - CS - PA - gas) with a recent experience of n.4 years in **construction supervision** as a **Civil-Structural-Architectural Handover Engineer** (administrative, Labs, production and classified clean room (E-D-C) areas)

At all times during my engagement on various projects, I conducted with utmost professionalism, and was an excellent team member, providing clear and unambiguous direction to the team in terms of what was required to meet the local authorities many requirements, and managing the interfaces with all the external entities involved without fuss.

I'm highly motivated, hardworking and driven person with a demonstrated ability to work effectively as part of a team and as an individual with a key skill in establishing and maintaining excellent working relationships with customers and colleagues.

### 03/2020 - 12/2021 - Lengnau (BE) - CSL Behring

Main responsibility was leading the CSA Labs/Office/Clean rooms handover, taking over the responsibility to be the first point of contact of the local Authorities for the building occupancy (GVB). I also join the QA/QC civil department in the definition of GMP standard documentation for clean rooms and labs driving also the construction activity covering the CSA supervisor role.

## 08/2018 - 03/2020 at NGM Biogen - Luterbach (SO)

I joined the project as a project engineer coordinating all the activities for the final building occupancy and permit to work with deep knowledge on fire protection requirements (VKF), machine and PED directives (2006/42/EC and 2014/68/EU - EKAS) becoming the main point of contact of the following cantonal authorities: AWA, SUVA, SGV, FM global, AfU supporting the client.

# 11/2016 - 08/2018 at GSK Vaccines - Siena (Italy)

I had the opportunity to follow the whole process of the project starting form the URS definition, coordinating the new equipment installation (FAT-SAT) and supervising the commissioning and qualification activities (IQ-PQ-OQ) related to the clean utilities generator equipment and relevant distributions.

#### **Education:**

2010-2015 – Master degree – Environmental Engineering.

#### Career:

2020 - 2021: CSL Behring 2018 - 2020: Biogen

2016 – 2018: GSK Vaccines

2015 -2016: Various pharmaceutical

companies:

- PFIZER MANUFACT. ITALY SRL
- CORDEN PHARMA LATINA
- BSP Pharmaceutical S.r.l.
- MENARINI BIOTECH S.r.l.

#### Skills:

Engineer Consultant
Clean utilities process and validation
Fire protection
Construction supervisor

GMP

EKAS directives
Machine directive 2006/42/EC
PED directive 2014/68/EU
Proportive

Proactive Analytic Team wor

Team worker Motivated

#### **Contacts:**

Contacts +41 788 822 30 25

+39 333 92 17 550

<u>giampaolo.carducci@gmail.com</u> https://www.giampaolocarducci.tk/